張凱鵬 (ZHANG, KAIPENG)

Tel: (86) 18817957729

E-mail: kpzhang@ut-vision.org

Homepage: http://kpzhang93.github.io/

About Me

I am a first-year Ph.D. student in Graduate School of Information Science and Technology at The University of Tokyo advised by Prof. Yoichi Sato. I received my M.S. degree in Graduate Institute of Networking and Multimedia at National Taiwan University in 2018. Before that, I received my B.E. degrees in 2016 from Donghua University.

I was a researcher in SenseTime and also did research internship at Microsoft Research Asia, Tencent AI Lab and MMLAB of CUHK at Shenzhen. My research interest mainly lies in computer vision, deep learning and focus on face analysis and open world analysis.









Education

Ph.D. - The University of Tokyo, Japan

04/2019 - 03/2022 (expected)

Graduate School of Information Science and Technology

supervised by Prof. Yoichi Sato

M.S. - National Taiwan University, Taiwan

09/2016 - 08/2018

Graduate Institute of Networking and Multimedia,

supervised by Prof. Winston Hsu.

GPA: 4.1/4.3

B.Eng. - Donghua University, China

09/2012 - 06/2016

Computer Network Engineering (Excellent Class)

GPA: 87/100

Experience

The University of Tokyo

04/2019 - 03/2022

Ph.D. student & Research assistant

Adviser: Prof. Yoichi Sato

Open-world analysis

09/2018 - 03/2019

SenseTime Researcher

Incremental large-scale face recognition learning

Visual Computing Group, Microsoft Research Asia

01/2018 - 07/2018

Research Intern

Mentor: Dr. Dong Chen

Large-scale face recognition

07/2017 - 09/2017

Tencent AI Lab Research Intern

Mentor: Dr. Zhifeng Li and Dr. Wei Liu

- Real-time face detection and alignment
- Two-stream contextual CNN with inside cascaded structure for face detection

Accepted by ICCV 2017

09/2016 - 08/2018

Master student & Research assistant

Adviser: Prof. Winston Hsu

National Taiwan University

Low-resolution face hallucination and recognition

- Accepted by ECCV 2018
- Virtual Try-On Shoe
 - Accepted by ACCV 2018
- Disguised Faces in the Wild
 - 1st winner of Disguised Faces in the Wild Challenge, CVPR 2018.
- Attribute Augmented Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination Accepted by CVPRW 2018
- Group-level emotion recognition in the wild
 - 1st winner of EmotionW, ICMI 2017 Grand Challenge
 - 2nd winner of EmotionW, ICMI 2018 Grand Challenge

Multimedia Laboratory, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology

07/2015 - 08/2016

Visiting student

Adviser: Prof. Zhifeng Li and Prof. Yu Qiao

- Face Recognition using proposed discriminative deep feature learning approach.
 Accepted by ECCV 2016 and IJCV
- Joint face detection and alignment using multi-task cascaded convolutional networks
 Accept by IEEE SPL
- Facial gender, smile and accessories classification using deep convolutional neural networks 1st winner of ChaLearn Looking at People Challenge Track 2 & 3, CVPR 2016.

Publications (received 1700+ citations, 06/30/2019)

- Yandong Wen*, Kaipeng Zhang*, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "A Comprehensive Study on Center Loss for Deep Face Recognition", IJCV, 2019 (* indicates equal contribution).
- Kaipeng Zhang, Zhanpeng Zhang, Chia-Wen Cheng, Winston Hsu, Yu Qiao, Wei Liu and Tong Zhang, "Super-Identity Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination", ECCV, 2018.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Ya-Liang Chang and Winston Hsu, "Deep Disguised Faces Recognition", CVPRW, 2018.
- Chao-Te Chou, Cheng-Han Lee, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Hu Cheng Lee and Winston Hsu, "Pose Invariant Virtual Try-On Shoe with Conditional Image Completion", *ACCV*, 2018.
- Kai Wang, Xiaoxing Zeng, Jianfei Yang, Debin Meng, Kaipeng Zhang, Xiaojiang Peng and Yu Qiao, "Cascade Attention Networks for Group Emotion Recognition with Face, Body and Image Cues", ICMI Grand Challenge, 2018.
- Cheng-Han Lee, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Hu Cheng Lee, Chia-Wen Cheng and Winston Hsu, "Attribute Augmented Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination", *CVPRW*, 2018.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Zhanpeng Zhang, Hao Wang, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao and Wei Liu, "Detecting Faces Using Inside Cascaded Contextual CNN", ICCV, 2017.
- Lianzhi Tan, Kaipeng Zhang, Kai Wang, Xiaoxing Zeng, Xiaojiang Peng and Yu Qiao, "Group Emotion Recognition with Individual Facial Emotion CNNs and Global Image Based CNNs", ICMI Grand Challenge, 2017
- Yandong Wen, Kaipeng Zhang, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "A Discriminative Deep Feature Learning Approach for Face Recognition", ECCV, 2016.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Zhanpeng Zhang, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "Joint Face Detection and Alignment using Multi-task Cascaded Convolutional Networks", *IEEE SPL*, vol. 23, no. 10, pp. 1499-1503, 2016.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Lianzhi Tan, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao, "Gender and Smile Classification using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks", CVPRW, 2016.

Selected Honors & Awards

Disguised Faces in the Wild Workshop, CVPR 2018, 1st winner	2018
Group-level emotion recognition, EmotiW, ICMI 2018 Grand Challenge, 2 nd winner	2018
Group-level emotion recognition, EmotiW, ICMI 2017 Grand Challenge, 1st winner	2017
Accessories Classification, ChaLearn Looking at People Challenging, CVPR 2016, Ist winner	2016
Smile and Gender Classification, ChaLearn Looking at People Challenging, CVPR 2016, 1st winner	2016
Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis	2016

Academic Service

Reviewer of ICCV 2019, CVPR (2018, 2019), ACCV 2018, TPAMI, TIP, TNNLS, Neurocomputing, and SPL